CERTISSIICH Creative Technologist & Front-End Developer

Chris is an excellent and skilled front-end developer with a design background. This allows him to do high-value technical work, with a perfectionist eye for user experience and user interface design.

He's fast learner, and a hard worker. He prides himself on being able to adapt quickly to face new design or development challenges and master ever-changing technologies and trends. He seeks to maintain a high level of quality in his work with a hard working attitude and a high attention to detail.

Technical Experience

Javascript: Vanilla, Node, Express, Vue, React, GSAP, CreateJS, Pixi

CSS: Grid, Flex, Float, Bootstrap, Material, BEM

PHP: Vanilla, Laravel, Wordpress

Design: XD, Figma, After Effects, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

Creative Tech: Unity Game Engine, Arduino C++

Back in the day: CodeIgniter, Flash, AS3, BASIC when I was about 8

Professional Experience

Creative Circus, 2013-Present

Program Director, Creative Technology

Directed two two-year portfolio programs: Creative Technology and Graphic Design. Primarily teaching, curriculum development, and any design, development, or technology work the school needed.

Taught web development from "hello world" to React and Vue.

Taught graphic design from pencil to print.

Taught creative tech from brainstorm to build.

Freelance, 2006-Present

Design and Development work, primarily websites, for small to medium size companies. Primarily Wordpress, some Laravel

Primal Screen, 2008-2013

Interactive Director

Worked on a broad spectrum of projects for television advertising, websites, web apps, mobile devices, touchscreens UI. Motion graphics, user experience design, Flash animation, web design and programming, game design and programming.

Education

Georgia State University Atlanta, Georgia

Bachelor's of Fine Arts Graphic Design, 2009

Accomplishments

One **Emmy** Nomination, Interactive Media Category Two **SEED** Design Awards Web Design Category

Contact

678-851-1069 chris.silich@gmail.com